

Software Engineer seeking roles in IT Project Management,Requirement Gathering,Software Development,Software Design,Technical Architecture,Bug Tracking,Debugging,Angularjs,Python,jQuery,JSON,MySQL,Bootstrap



Current Designation: Software Engineer- Angular developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 10 Month(s)

Current Company: L&T Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: BE [CS]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Pune
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software

Development, Software Design, Technical Architecture, Bug

Tracking, Debugging, Angularis, Python, jQuery, JSON, MySQL, Bootstrap

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

## Summary

Innovative and a proven team player with a tech degree in Computer Science and 4 years' experience of building, developing, and managing websites, applications, and programs for various organizations. Coming with Certifications in Angular, JavaScript and basics of Python. Interested in securing the position of Senior developer, hoping to learn and share great skills, expertise, and experience with company's team and valuable clients

# **Work Experience**

**L&T** as Software Engineer- Angular developer Sep 2018 to Till Date

Responsible for developing UI pages using Angular, HTML, JavaScript, Prime NG, and Bootstrap

- \* Used Angular custom directives and developed components and templates
- \* Worked with Angular to develop Single page applications and with RXJS to manage applications
- \* Extensively worked on reusable components and services to consume REST APIs
- \* Implemented HTTP requests using RXJS observable library
- \* Used Jasmine/Karma for Unit testing
- \* Used TFS to keep track of bugs to reduce downtime, increase productivity and Communication
- \* Worked extensively on Angular CLI for creating new components, directives, pipes, services, and used NPM installing required modules
- \* Developed a basic Python application to fetch data from Database and save in XML file Used Augury and Firebug to debug the application on JavaScript DOM and carry out modifications with local storage and session storage data
- \* Implemented dynamic Comments section for user to log his feeds, and will be updated for every user logged in using Angular
- \* Developed dynamic Tab shift for Main menus based on search results of the Search functionality developed for application
- \* Worked extensively in Agile development process
- \* Carried out CRUD operations on MySQL for basic operations on application

Environments: Angular, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JSON, TypeScript, Angular CLI, REST, Prime NG, Bootstrap, RXJS, Team Foundation Server, Jasmine, Karma, NPM, Augury, Firebug, Agile methodology, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, MySQL

## Telloquent Solutions Pvt Ltd as UI Developer

Sep 2017 to Apr 2018

Responsibilities

- \* Developed cross-browser/platform HTML 4/5, CSS 3 and JavaScript to match design specs for complex layouts adhering to code standards
- \* Worked extensively on email templates, landing pages and E-commerce websites using advanced jQuery plugins for animations, drag and drop etc., and consuming RESTful services and JSON for data transfer
- \* Developed POCs to create a user interface in Angular as a Single-page application
- \* Implemented client side drop down menus, Search bars, drop-down toggles, Accordions using latest Twitter Bootstrap
- \* Used Firebug and Augury to debug JavaScript to analyse DOM object of pages developed with new features of HTML 5 like section, article, header, footer, canvas for animations
- \* Proficiency in building responsive and mobile optimized websites using Bootstrap Environments: HTML 4/5, CSS 3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, AJAX, JSON, SPA, REST APIs, Angular JS, Firebug, Augury, Responsive design

# CodeRapper as Front End Developer

Sep 2016 to Sep 2017

Responsibilities

- \* Developed UI deliverables, such as wireframes, screen mock-ups, and interface design specs using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS
- \* Participated in making responsive web designs using Media Queries and Twitter Bootstrap
- \* Developed E-commerce applications using Shopify, HTML, DOM, JavaScript, and CSS based
- \* Created animation effects during data load and waiting for response from API
- \* Performed Client-side validation for Forms using JavaScript

Environments: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM, jQuery, Shopify, Media Queries, JavaScript Validation and Bootstrap

#### Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Visveswaraya Technological University in 2016

PG: **BE (CS)** in **0** 

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version I	Last Used	Experience
Angular 2/4/5,React,HTML,CSS			
JavaScript,Bootstrap,Notepad ++			
TypeScript,AJAX,JQuery			
Angular CLI,JSON,Prime NG			
Python,RXJS			
TFS, Git,Sublime Text			
MySQL			
Visual Studio Code			

### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No